I'm in Washington, D.C. right now, and I
want to visualize for you what it would
look like if a nuclear weapon landed on
the nation's capital. So, for our
scenario, there is a nuclear weapon
headed towards the city right now.
A large nuclear weapon flying headed
towards Washington, D.C.
The actual bomb is actually in here.
This cone that's about 2 m tall, 6 ft.
It's falling back into the atmosphere.
Here it comes.
And then
for a moment, right here is the hottest
thing in our solar system, hotter than
the sun.
100 million degrees Celsius as it
expands out. [music]
Everything around it turns into dust. I
mean, smaller than dust. Atoms are
ripped apart. This fireball instantly
vaporizes everything within a half-mile
radius.
And here comes the blast wave. A wall of
high-pressure air that is moving faster
than the speed of sound. It creates wind
behind it that is faster than anything
ever observed in nature.
Everything within 2 and 1/2 miles is
leveled. [music]
And then there's the heat wave, which
burns everything within 5 miles. Nearly
everyone in this city is either dead or
severely injured.
Everything that can be on fire is now on
fire as this huge mushroom cloud rises
into the air, dragging with it a storm
of dust, dirt, and debris.
But this isn't normal dust anymore.
The bomb has done something to it, to
its atoms, making them fall apart in
slow motion, shooting out invisible
deadly energy. This poison dust drifts
all across this region. It clings to
soil and plants and people hundreds of
miles away.
These poisoned atoms will keep firing
off radiation for [music] years, for
decades, centuries, even thousands of
years. This is a disaster that humans
made, and that was just for one of these
cones.
>> [music]
>> A rocket fired from an American
submarine
can carry eight of these cones at once.
If all of those hit one target, it would
be a much worse situation.
>> [music]
>> A lot of global politics centers around
this, making sure this does not happen.
But everything I just showed you is very
possible. We have the capabilities to do
this right now. And in fact, a lot of
countries have their finger on the
trigger, able to launch one of these at
a moment's notice.